Guide to the Irving Fisher Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- MICROFILM INVENTORY
  - Miscellaneous Essays, Vol. III: "General", 1931 - 1947
    - 1942
      - "After the War What?," address at Wilmington, Del. released, 1942 Jan 15 (Box 9)
        - Same title ( Biosophical Review, N.Y.C.), 1942 (Box 9)
      - "International Law Must Replace War" ( Flashes, New Haven Rotary), 1942 Mar 21 (Box 9)
      - "After the War What?" ( Christian Advocate ), 1942 Apr 16 (Box 9)
        - Same ( The Nation, Colombo), 1942 Aug 29 (Box 9)
      - "Winning the Peace," St. Louis address, release, 1942 Jun 27 (Box 9)
        - Same in Post-Dispatch, St. Louis, 1942 Jun 28 (Box 9)
        - Editorial re same ( Nowiny Polskie (Polish) Milwaukee, Wis.), 1942 Jul 18 (Box 9)
      - "Forced Loans Urged" ( Register, New Haven), 1942 Nov 20 (Box 9)
    - 1943
      - Leaflet endorsing Equal Rights Amendment, 1943 (Box 9)
      - "A World Map on a Regular Icosahedron by Gnomonic Projection" ( Geographical Review ), 1943 (Box 9)
        - Same discussed in W. Kaempffert's Science Column ( Times, New York), 1943 Oct 3 (Box 9)
    - 1944
      - Comments on Dr. Lohman's "What Price Econ. Security?" ( Commercial & Financial Chronicle, N.Y.C.), 1944 Aug 3 (Box 9)
      - "Lauds Outcome of Bretton Woods Conference," same paper, 1944 Aug 17 (Box 9)
      - Europe Going Socialist, by John MacCormac ( Times, New York), 1944 Nov 20 (Box 9)
        - Editorial re same ( Times, N.Y.C.), 1944 Nov 26 (Box 9)
        - Letter to Editor re same ( Times ), 1944 Dec 4 (Box 9)
      - "Private Enterprise Needed," letter to Editor ( Times, New York), 1944 Dec 13 (Box 9)
      - "Free Enterprise Defined," letter to Editor ( Times, New York), 1944 Dec 22 (Box 9)
    - 1945
      - "Reveals Mussolini Talk" ( Register, New Haven, Ct.), 1945 Jul 29 (Box 9)
      - "Golden Era of Post-War Prosperity Seen" ( Star Times, St. Louis, Mo.), 1945 Sep 27 (Box 9)
      - Letter to Editor ( Fortune, New York), 1945 Nov (Box 9)
    - 1946
      - Another letter to Editor ( Fortune, New York), 1946 Aug (Box 9)
      - Tribute to I.F. by Ragnar Frisch, and Reply ( Journal of American Statis. Association ), 1947 March (Box 9)
    - Added: 1958 Apr 13
      - "Ink in My Veins," by Cornelius Vanderbilt, Jr., quoting Irving Fisher re: England going off the Gold Standard (Box 9)
      - Description of changes at Yale in 1887 letter from Irving Fisher to Norman Flogg, N.H. Journal-Courier, June 10, 1967. (Box 9)
  - Appendix to Economic Essays, Vol. XVII
    - "Short Stories on Wealth" trans. into Chinese by Franklin L. Ho (Published by Ta-Kung-Pao, Weekly Econ. Supplement, Tientsin)
      - Chapter 1. The Main Idea, 1930 August 31 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 2. Capital Accounts, 1930 September 7 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 3. Income Accounts, 1930 September 14 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 4. Relation between Capital and Income, 1930 September 21 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 5. What money is not, 1930 September 28 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 6. What money is and is for, 1930 October 5 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 6. What money is and is for (cont.), 1930 October 12 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 7. Credit currency, 1930 October 19 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 8. The Purchasing Power of Money, 1930 October 26 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 9. What Fixes the Purchasing Power of the Dollar, 1930 November 2, 1930 November 9 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 10. How Inflation and Deflation Work, 1930 November 16 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 11. The Flowing Streams of Money and Goods, 1930 November 23 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 12. Continuation of 11, 1930 November 30, 1930 December 7 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 13. Supply and Demand, 1930 December 14 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 47. Population and Poverty--continued, 1930 December 21 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 15. Changes in Supply and Demand, 1930 December 28 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 16. "What's Back of Demand?", 1931 January 12 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 17. Why the Rich Demand More than the Poor, 1931 February 2 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 18. The Influences behind Supply, 1931 February 9 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 19. Monopoly Price, 1931 February 23 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 20. Cut-throat Competition, 1931 March 2 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 21. Cut-throat Competition Leads to Monopoly, 1931 March 9 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 22. The Future, not the Past, Rules Value, 1931 March 16 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 23. The Riddle of Interest, 1931 March 23 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 24. Is Interest taking Wrong?, 1931 March 30 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 25. Wrong Explanations of Interest, 1931 April 6 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 26. Real Interest and Money, 1931 April 13 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 27. Impatience to Spend, 1931 April 20 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 28. [no information available]
      - Chapter 29. The Impersonal Factors in Impatience, 1931 May 4 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 30. How Impatience Influences Interest, 1931 May 11 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 31. Opportunity for Investment, 1931 May 18 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 32. Before Leaving the Subject of Price, 1931 May 25 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 33. Distribution, 1931 June 1 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 34. Rent, 1931 June 8 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 35. Land Rent, 1931 June 15 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 36. Wages, 1931 June 22 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 37. Demand for Labor, 1931 June 29 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 38. Wages and Total Earnings of Labor, 1931 July 8 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 39. Labor Efficiency, 1931 July 13 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 40. Wages and Employers' Profits, 1931 July 20 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 41. Profits and Wages Continued, 1931 July 20 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 42. The Capitalist Employer, 1931 July 27 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 43. No Title (The Capitalist Employer contd.), 1931 August 3 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 44. Personal Distribution, 1931 August 10 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 45. National Wealth or Poverty, 1931 August 17 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 46. Population and Poverty, 1931 August 24 (Box 9)
      - (Furer, M. & Mahler, M.) "Development of Symbiosis, Symbiotic Psychosis and the Nature of Separation Anxiety--Remarks on Weiland's Paper," 47:559-561., 1931 August 31 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 48. No Title (Population and Wealth), 1931 September 7 (Box 9)
      - Chapter 49. Distribution, 1931 September 14 (Box 9)